Contact

radu@zerodawn.tech

www.linkedin.com/in/radu-chiriac (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Linux System Administration
Python (Programming Language)
Back-End Web Development

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Italian (Limited Working)
Romanian (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

CompTIA Linux+ ce Certification
Create and Manage Cloud
Resources

Radu Chiriac

Technical Engineer - HPC Services

Braşov, Romania

Summary

I have been working in the IT and Tech Support fields for over 15 years starting from a Level 1 Call Center Agent up to my current position in High Performance Computing.

Out of a desire to continuously improve and acquire new skills, I have also learned Python Programming, Cloud Computing and DevOps.

I have also created a few websites for different Python Projects during 100 Days of Code course. See my Projects section or my Github for details.

Experience

Eviden

HPC Technical Engineer
July 2023 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Braşov, Romania

- Eviden is an Atos business.
- Supporting the server infrastructure for a German auto maker for one of it's most critical projects.
- Using Puppet for configuration management and automatic patching of RHEL 7.9 servers.
- Monitoring the infrastructure using ManageNow for Datacenter Monitoring (MN4DCM) from Fujitsu.
- Participating in a project to migrate existing remote locations to a more streamlined solution.

Atos IT Solutions and Services A/S
Technical Engineer - HPC Services
February 2022 - July 2023 (1 year 6 months)

Braşov, Romania

- Supporting the server infrastructure for a German auto maker for one of it's most critical projects..

- Reviewing all the existing technical documentation and updating it accordingly to the current requirements.
- Using Puppet for configuration management and automatic patching of RHEL 7.9 servers.
- Monitoring the infrastructure using ManageNow for Datacenter Monitoring (MN4DCM) from Fujitsu.

CGS Romania

9 years 7 months

Technical Support Engineer
April 2020 - February 2022 (1 year 11 months)

Braşov, Romania

Handling support tickets raised by admins that use an laaS to integrate their business needs with cloud applications.

This implies gathering all relevant data and logs, researching for the root cause, finding a solution and applying it in the customer's tenant.

L2 Technical Mentor

April 2018 - April 2020 (2 years 1 month)

Brasov, Romania

The position entitles providing guidance and technical advice to the team, improving quality of service provided and escalating complex issues to the Level 3 and above teams.

Technical Support Agent

October 2014 - April 2018 (3 years 7 months)

Bucharest, Romania

I'm responsible for providing warranty and technical support for Lenovo's business customers based in UK and Ireland.

Support is offered by phone, email and remote connection.

Back Office Employee

August 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 3 months)

- Perform eligibility checks for the employees of one of USA's major telecom company and process orders for them;
- Customer support by e-mail;
- Offering support to my colleagues when the Team Leader is busy or absent;
- Tasked with accommodating the new hires with the work environment and procedures;

Mediafax

Monitoring Editor August 2009 - April 2010 (9 months)

Responsible with making short reviews based on key words that appeared in TV news for the company's clients

Education

Universitatea "Spiru Haret" din București International Relations and European Studies, International Relations and Affairs · (October 2003 - July 2007)

Technical College "Gheorghe Cartianu"

Baccalaureate, Mechanical Engineering Related Technologies/
Technicians · (September 1999 - June 2003)